wadhwani-foundation.org 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Wadhwani Foundation

**Statement of Privacy and Use**

This Statement of Privacy and Use (the “Statement”) describes the online information practices of the Wadhwani Foundations (the “Foundations”). It explains the information the Foundations collects through its website (the “Site”), how the Foundations may use the Data it collects, and the conditions regarding use of the Foundations Site. The Foundations reserves the right to modify this Statement at any time without prior notification to persons using the Site.

 **General Information/Collection and Use of Data**

We welcome the public to visit our Site, which can be browsed without the need to submit any personal information online. For those visitors who visit our Site without registering or signing up for newsletters, we may collect your internet protocol address, the name of your internet service provider, the browser and type of machine you are using, the website that referred you to us, and the pages of our Site that you visit (the “Public Information”). For those who visit our Site through registering or signing up for our electronic newsletters, we will collect the Public Information described above and the data you provide to us voluntarily on the data forms, such as your name and company affiliation (the “Visitor Information”). The Public Information and the Visitor Information is collectively referred to herein as the “Data”.

The Data collected from you may be used by the Foundations generally to improve the Site, to provide you with newsletters, articles, and other items of interest, to generate usage or demographic statistics so that we may better understand your needs, to measure Site activity, and to improve the Site’s structure in helping users better reach needed information, all of which is intended to enhance the usefulness of the Site to our visitors. We may also use the Data to educate ourselves about the interests and concerns of our visitors for purposes of better serving the community and our grantees. We will not use any Data for commercial purposes. Any use of this Site for commercial purposes is strictly prohibited.

 **Technology**

The Foundations and vendors acting on its behalf may use the Data in combination with various Internet technologies to help manage Site operations, track user traffic, and gather broad demographic information.

We may use Internet Protocol (IP) addresses (i.e., a number assigned by your Internet Service Provider so you can access the Internet) to diagnose possible technical problems, administer our Site, and aggregate Data on use. Log files, which identify every request made to our server, may be used to determine statistically which areas of the Site our visitors prefer and to prepare future content based on the interests of our visitors.

We may also use “cookies” to better serve our visitors. A “cookie” is a small data file that certain websites write to your computer’s hard drive when you access the site. A cookie file can contain information, such as a user ID, that a website uses to track the pages you have visited, but the only personal information a cookie contains is information you supply. Cookies may also allow our Site to recognize and load your pages on repeat visits to the Site. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites.

Our site and HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters may use web beacons in conjunction with cookies to understand a visitor’s behavior. A web beacon (also called a single-pixel or clear GIF) is an electronic image that can recognize certain types of information on a visitor’s computer, such as a visitor’s cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the web beacon is placed. Some web beacons may be unusable if you elect to reject their associated cookies. We may also use customized links or other similar technologies to track e-mail links that you select. We may associate personal information with the Data in order to provide you more focused e-mail communications. Each e-mail communication includes an unsubscribe link allowing you to stop delivery of that type of communication.

If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website or via HTML-formatted e-mails, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of our Site if you do so. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use/navigate through the Site, although access to and use of the Site might be limited at times.

 **Electronic Newsletters and Databases**

Following your registration on our Site, the Foundations will provide you with electronic newsletters that it publishes from time to time. The newsletters describe the work of the Foundations grantees and the benefits that the work brings to the community at large. The Data, including the information entered by you on our Site, is provided on a confidential basis to one or more third-party service providers that we engage to maintain contact databases and/or send messages on our behalf. The Data may also be aggregated with or linked to information already existing in the database. Each electronic newsletter message that is sent will indicate how you may unsubscribe if you so desire.

 **External Links**

This site contains links to other sites. The Foundations provides such links to help visitors explore the wide range of information available on topics of interest. The Foundations is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the other linked websites. By providing a link, the Foundations is not endorsing the content of the linked site or the entity that maintains it. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Statement applies solely to information collected by this Site.

 **Confidentiality**

The Foundations is the sole owner of the Data collected on the Site. The Foundations will not sell, rent, share, exchange, or otherwise disclose the Data to others outside of the Foundations (or consultants or agents retained by the Foundations), except as described in this Statement. The Foundations will attempt to collect and store the Data in a manner to protect its confidentiality, recognizing that no transmission of data is entirely secure.

We may disclose or provide Data pursuant to subpoenas, warrants, or other judicial or government orders, in the event an individual’s safety or security is at risk, or as otherwise required by law.

 **Unsubscribe**

Our Site and our electronic newsletter messages provide users the opportunity to opt out of receiving future automated communications from us.

 **Disclaimers and Limitation of Liability**

THE MATERIALS ON THIS SITE ARE PROVIDED “AS IS” TO VISITORS. THE FOUNDATIONS DOES NOT REPRESENT THAT THE INFORMATION IS COMPLETE, CURRENT, ERROR-FREE, OR APPLICABLE TO YOUR SITUATION. ALTHOUGH WE INTEND TO TAKE REASONABLE STEPS TO PREVENT THE INTRODUCTION OF VIRUSES, WORMS, “TROJAN HORSES” OR OTHER DESTRUCTIVE MATERIALS TO OUR SITE, WE DO NOT GUARANTEE OR WARRANT THAT OUR SITE, OR MATERIALS THAT MAY BE DOWNLOADED FROM OUR SITE, ARE FREE FROM SUCH DESTRUCTIVE FEATURES. ANY MATERIALS OBTAINED FROM THIS SITE OR DOWNLOADED FROM THE SITE ARE OBTAINED OR DOWNLOADED AT YOUR OWN RISK. THE FOUNDATIONS ASSUMES NO LIABILITY OR RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY DAMAGES ARISING FROM A VISITOR’S USE OF, OR INABILITY TO USE, THIS SITE. THE FOUNDATIONS SHALL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OR HARM TO COMPUTER SYSTEMS, LOSS OF DATA RESULTING FROM THE DOWNLOAD OF ANY MATERIALS, AND WE DISCLAIM WARRANTIES FOR ANY INFORMATION RECEIVED THROUGH ANY LINKS PROVIDED BY THIS SITE. THE FOUNDATIONS IS NOT LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY BASED ON ERRORS, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS OR OTHER INACCURACIES IN THIS SITE, NOR FOR ANY CLAIM, LOSS OR INJURY THAT RESULTS FROM YOUR USE OF THIS SITE.

 **Updates**

We may update this Statement from time to time and encourage you to check back periodically and review the Foundations most updated Statement.

 **Questions**

If you have any questions regarding this Statement, please contact the Foundations.
